shoebaloo.nl 2017-06-06

# Privacy Statement | Shoebaloo

**Privacy Statement** SHOEBALOO b.v. ('SHOEBALOO', 'we', 'our', 'us' ) respects the privacy rights of its online visitors and customers ('you', 'your', 'yours'). SHOEBALOO recognizes the importance of protecting the information collected about the online visitors and customers.

This Privacy policy is created to help you understand what we may do with any information you provide us with. Every visitor on the SHOEBALOO website is able to surf the website without providing your personal information, unless you log in with your email address and password. `     

For our visitors or customers under the age of 18, we require that they inform a parent or guardian about SHOEBALOO’s Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions. We require the consent of the parent or guardian to the Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions before registering with SHOEBALOO or placing an order with SHOEBALOO.     

By providing your personal information to us, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy and agree that we may collect, use and disclose your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into, and part of, the Terms and Conditions, which govern your use of the website maintained and operated by SHOEBALOO the online store. To ensure optimal service we save some of your personal information. When signing in on the SHOEBALOO website your name, address, and place of residence will be saved on our server. You have the full right to request or correct or delete these information. You could contact us through our customer care e-mail customercare@shoebaloo.nl 

Your information will only be used for the purposes set out below.         

_Use of personal data_        

SHOEBALOO specifies that the use of personal data is necessary to execute the required services. Users are assured that the use of such data will not be used for profiling research, but solely to facilitate site management and the execution of orders. 

1. When you place an order, SHOEBALOO will ask you for your name, telephone number, e-mail address, delivery address, billing address, the way of payment, credit/debit card number, expiry date, security code to process and to complete the order. Card details will never be shared with third parties and only will be used to process your order, using our payment partner’s system.   
All the necessary information required in order for credit card payment and transactions to be processed (credit/debit card number, expiry date, security code) will be sent to our bank ABN AMRO and Ingenico. Ingenico is a company that offers technological solutions for online payment in e-commerce and an interface between credit card companies, banks, merchants and consumers, when online payment on the SHOEBALOO online store occurs. We make arrangements with these companies according to contract with regard to the handling of your personal data in order to secure your privacy. The bank information will never be saved and every offered way of payment is secured. 

2. When subscribing for the SHOEBALOO newsletter on our website, your e-mail address could be used for marketing purposes. By subscribing you give SHOEBALOO the permission to do so. In any cases your e-mail address will not be shared with third parties. At any time you can opt out (unsubscribe) for our newsletter by sending us an e-mail: customercare@shoebaloo.nl

3. SHOEBALOO may monitor your surf behavior to gather information about visitors on our website. We might observe your way of navigation on the SHOEBALOO website, the most viewed pages, the selected items and the ordered products. We might recognize repeat visitors for statistical/ analytical purposes or anonymous tracking for online advertising purposes. The objective for monitoring the traffic on the SHOEBALOO website is to improve the SHOEBALOO formula. Your private information will not be used for monitoring the traffic and we are not able to match a certain surf behavior to a certain account on the SHOEBALOO website. 

_Cookies  _

A cookie is a piece of information that is stored on your computer's hard drive by your web browser which tracks your movements within websites. Our site uses cookies to keep track of how often you visit our site, the contents of your shopping cart, previous purchases and to deliver content specific to your interests. Most browsers are automatically set to accept cookies but usually you can alter the settings of your browser to prevent automatic acceptance. If you choose not to receive cookies, you may still use most of the features of our website, including the ability to purchase items. For more information on cookies and how to disable them, you can consult the information provided by the Interactive Advertising Bureau at www.allaboutcookies.org 

 _Security measures_   

The security measures on the SHOEBALOO website are intended to avoid the risk of unauthorized access or dispersion of data that may cause any personal risk to the security of our clients. SHOEBALOO has implemented appropriate organizational and technical security measures to protect the users and their data. 

Despite this effort, SHOEBALOO cannot guarantee that these security measures will limit and exclude any and all risk of unauthorized access to this information. For this reason, we advise our visitors and customers to navigate on the SHOEBALOO website only from a secure (computer) source. 

SHOEBALOO makes every effort to prevent data leaks. In the event of an unexpected data leak, SHOEBALOO has a data-leak protocol in place, which is consistently enforced.          

_Retention period of personal data_

We will only keep your information for as long as is strictly necessary for the purposes for which it was collected and always in accordance with the law.  

 _Rights of parties concerned_

If you wish to find out if SHOEBALOO is processing your personal data, please send a written inspection request together with your point of view where relevant, to: 

SHOEBALOO shall deal with an inspection request within 4 weeks’ time. If any personal data are being processed, SHOEBALOO shall forward to you a complete and organized statement of such personal data, including a description of the purpose of the processing, the data to which the processing is related, the recipients and the available information about the origin of the personal data. At your request, SHOEBALOO shall also notify you of the logics on which the automated processing of the personal data is based. If it should unexpectedly appear that the personal data are incorrect, incomplete or not relevant, you may make an additional request in order to have the personal data adjusted or supplemented.

 _Amendments_

SHOEBALOO reserves the right to adjust or amend this privacy statement. None of the provisions in this privacy statement are for the purpose of establishing any obligation or agreement between SHOEBALOO and a party concerned.
